American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Note to the American philosophical society, 1892; 7-1/4x5-1/4; Wilson, Louis N., 1857-1937
    A.N.S. 1p. on fragment of galley proof. Address of George Baur.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [1892]; 8-1/4x5; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns copies of report on publication of transcripts of Babylonian tablets. For report, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, vol.30, pp.266-267.
  - Note on calling card to [Henry] Phillips, [1892]; 2-1/2x4-1/4; Vossion, Louis, 1847-1906
    Phila., A.N.S. 1p. Announces death of Quatrefages. Will be happy to write his obituary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, [1892?]; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Hofmann, August Wilhelm von, 1818-1892
    Berlin, A.L. in 3d person 1p., end. 50th anniversary of his degree of doctor of philosophy.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [1892?]; 9x6; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Health is poor. Veiled reference to election of R.
  - Note to [Henry Phillips], 1892; 9x5-3/4; Morison, Ella M.
    ] A.N.S. 1p. and end. Tells him of Price's suggestion for storing catalogues in library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 3, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends books for library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 4, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Weymouth Heights, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Plates found, and given to B. Meisel. Has received galley proofs from MacCalla.
  - Letter to J. H. Schwarz, Jan. 5, 1893; 13-1/2x8; Austro-Hungary. K. und K. post- und telegraphen-direction für Böhmen.
    Prague, Typed L. 2p. His letters to A.P.S. are not delivered because he uses the wrong address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 5, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Weymouth Heights, A.L.S. 2p. Apologizes for trouble over plates which he feared lost.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 5, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Keim, George de Benneville
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Health prevented him from attending election meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 5, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend next meeting.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 7, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires whether A.P.S. wants his paper on Lewis and Clark journals.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 10, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Seligman, Edwin R. A. (Edwin Robert Anderson), 1861-1939
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns Studies in History, Economics, and Public Law.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 11, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Thanks A.P.S. for extended loan of Lewis and Clark journals. Presents his description of the journals for publication in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 13, 1893; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Boston Public Library
    Boston, L.S.: Theodore F. Dwight, Librarian. 1p., end. Asks for Proceedings issued since April, 1893.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 13, 1893; 3x4-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Approves printing of Boas' Kwakiutl vocabulary. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 31, pp. 34-82.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 4p. Cannot attend library committee meeting. Refers to books for library, its new quarters, J.C. Morris, E. Coues, Lewis and Clark journals, E.J. Houston.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 16, 1893; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Boston Public Library
    Boston, L.S.: Theodore F. Dwight, Librarian. 1p. Concerns Proceedings issued since April 1892.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1893; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Boston Public Library
    Boston, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end., and end. Thanks for gift of Proceedings,
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1893; 13-1/2x8; Schwarz, J. H.
    Kladno, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Concerns his error in address of A.P.S. Sends letter from Austrian post office. For enclosure, see Austro-Hungary. K. and K. post- und telegraphen-direction... to J. H. Schwarz,
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Acting Belgian Consul, Jan. 18, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Austria. consul. Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: Lars Westergaard, Consul. 2p. Concerns coming of a certain un-named gentleman, which is to be kept secret.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 18, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Will read a paper on the fauna of the latest Cenozoic (Equus) beds of the Staked Plains. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, p. 11.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1893; 8-1/4x5-3/4; Edwards, Mrs. A. F.
    Bloomfield, Cal., A.L.S. 1p., and end. Asks for copy of report on spelling reform. Discusses Volapük and Spelin.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 21, 1893; 8x5; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns printing of his work on the transcription of Babylonian tablets. Refers to P. DuBois, Mr. Partridge, and MacCalla & Co.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 21, 1893; 5-1/2x8, 3-1/2x6; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., L. 1p. and add., end. Concerns cost of extra copies of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Daniel Garrison] Brinton, Jan. 23, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p., end. by Brinton to Phillips. Concerns proof of Boas' article on Kwakiutl language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 23, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I. A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends paper on moths for publication. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 83-108.
  - Letter to A[lpheus] S[pring] Packard, Jan. 27, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 2p. Copy. Concerns plates for his papers on moths. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 83-108.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 28, 1893; 8x5, 3-1/4x5, 2-1/2x3-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, [R.I.], A.L.S. 2p. and add. Enc. Concerns drawings for paper on moths. Sends sample drawing. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, PP. 83-108.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 30, 1893; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Boston Public Library
    Boston, L.S.: Theodore F. Dwight, Librarian. 1p. Concerns Proceedings issued since April, 1892.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 30, 1893; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Will read a paper on the fauna of the Eurystylus and Equus beds of the Staked Plains. Not mentioned in the Proceedings for 1893 or 1894.
  - Invoice to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1893; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Loescher & Seeber
    Florence, D. 1p. and end. Sends book for examination.
  - Letter to Henry W. Philps [sic], Feb. 2, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Will prepare paper on Wealth and Resources of Pennsylvania to present to A.P.S. Will request A.P.S. aid inpreparing an exhibit on the subject for the World's Fair.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 2, 1893; 3x5; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns drawings for his paper on moths. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 31, pp. 83-108.
  - Report in response to Society's resolution of Dec. 16, 1892, Feb. 3, 1893; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.,] Typed D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris, R[ichard] Meade Bache, Patterson DuBois 1p., end., and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns arrangement and storage of A.P.S. collections. For resolution, see A.P.S. Resolution... Dec. 16, 1892. Cf. Proceedings, v.30, p.315.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 3, 1893; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Boston Public Library
    Boston, L. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings, No.139.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Feb. 4, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S 1p. About his paper on wealth and resources of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 4, 1893; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns reply to Smithers, about loan of material to Columbian Exposition. See A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 31, p. 12.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1893; 8x5-1/4; Holmes & Nichols
    Boston, l. 1p., end. Change of address for E.F. Im Thurn.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 8, 1893; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, [R.I.], A.L.S. 1p., and end. Encs. wanting. Sends sketches for his paper on moths. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 83-108.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 9, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends proof of his article on Lewis and Clark journals. Inquires about extras. Refers to his edition of the journals.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 11, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Salem, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. Concerns his paper on Saprolegniaceae. Refers to MacCalla & co., Meisel. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 63-148.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 11, 1893; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, [R.I.], A.L.S. 1p., and end. Encs. wanting. Sends rest of sketches for his paper on moths. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings. vol. 31, pp. 83-108.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [Feb. 15], 1893; 7-3/4x5; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Mutilated. Concerns library.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 16, 1893; 8-1/4x5; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks address of Cope. Discusses the Council's decision on return of A.P.S. collections. Refers to Academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 18, 1893; 3x5-1/4; American antiquarian and oriental journal
    Avon, III., Printed L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philipps [sic], Feb. 21, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting. Sends half-tone reproductions to be used in his paper, "Old Babylonian inscriptions chiefly from Nippur," APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp.5-54, 221-282. Refers to Partridge, Brinton.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 21, 1893; 8x5; Schäffer, Charles, 1838-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends cheque for initiation fee and life membership. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 23, 1893; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Refers to Sesquicentennial celebration committee, J.T. Rothrock. Announces death of F.A. Genth. Appoints G.F. Barker to prepare obituary.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 7, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Recommends purchase of books.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 7, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Thompson, Robert Ellis, 1844-1924
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Letter of resignation.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philipps [sic;], March 8, 1893; 5-1/4x3; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of his paper on old Babylonian inscriptions. Refers to Partridge, MacCalla & co. For paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp.5-54, 221-282.
  - Letter to Henry Philips, March 8, 1893; Muhlenberg, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1818-1901
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 9, 1893; 8x5; Dolley, Charles S.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of his paper on "The Thyrsos of Dionysos and the Palm Inflorescence of the Winged Figures of Assyrian Monuments." For printed paper, see: APS. Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 109-116.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 10, 1893; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns engraved portraits of members.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 10, 1893; 8-1/2x6; Meisel, Berthold
    Boston, L. 1p. Has sent proofs of plates for J.E. Humphrey's paper on Saprolegniaceae. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 63-148.
  - Report upon the Society's resolution of Oct. 7, 1892, March 11, 1893; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators (: APS Archives VI, 1)
    [Phila.,] Typed D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris, R[ichard] Meade Bache, Patterson DuBois 1p., end.: Read 3/11/93 (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Curators recommend loan of articles to Columbian Exposition. Cf. Proceedings, v.31, p.12.
    Located in APS Archives VI, 1
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 14, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to assist bearer, John Collins.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 16, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Gives opinion on return of Poinsett and numismatic collections to the A.P.S. Mentions death of W.B. Rogers.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 17, 1893; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Goodwin, Harold, 1850?-1935
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Gives opinion on exhibition of A.P.S. collections.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 18, 1893; 8-1/4x6; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1855?-1910
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. Encs. wanting. Sends photographs of himself and father.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 18, 1893; 8x5; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Weymouth Heights, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Names of lithographer is B. Meisel. Refers to son, J.E.Humphrey.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 18, 1893; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Mutilated. Enc. wanting. Sends resignation of R.E. Thompson.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 24, 1893; 11x8-1/2; St. Louis Mercantile Library Association
    St. Louis, Mo., A.L.S.: Horace Kephart, Librarian, 1p., end. Asks for copy of printed catalogue.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1893; 10x8; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about paper by G.B. Simpson on palaeozoic fossils. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 16, pp. 435-460.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 5, 1893; 9-3/4x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Asheville, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires date of Sesquicentennial Celebration.
  - Bill for lithographing plates, to the American philosophical society, April 5, 1893; 5x8; Meisel, Berthold
    Boston, Printed D. filled in in Ms. 1p. Plates are those for J.E. Humphrey's paper on Saprolegniaceae, in APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 63-148.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] Fraley, April 5, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Pennsylvania. Board of World's fair managers
    Harrisburg, Typed L.S.: John A. Woodward. 2p. Asks to borrow the Haldeman collection of Indian relics for World's Fair at Chicago.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 6, [1893]; 3x4-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Unable to attend meeting of Sesquicentennial Committee.
  - Letter to George F[rederick] Barker, April 8, 1893; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about his paper on gases. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 12, [1893]; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, [Pa.] A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on gases submitted for publication through G.F. Barker. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 13, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Pittsburg, Pa., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns printing of his paper on gases. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Report on damage done to Museum collection by its rearrangement, April 14, 1893; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris, R[ichard] Meade Bache, Patterson DuBois 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Accompanied by letters from J.S. Price to J.C. Morris and Morris to H. Phillips, April 21, 1893.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 15, 1893; 9-3/4x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Asheville, N.C., A.L.S. 2p. Suggests paper on Pennsylvania German customs for Sesquicentennial celebration memorial volume. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 325-331.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 15, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will speak on iron-making in the U.S. at next meeting.
  - Letter to [Richard] Vaux, April 18, 1893; 10-3/4x8; Sheppard, Furman, 1823-1893
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Sends topics for consideration by committee on Phillips essay prize.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 19, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his subscription to the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot attend meeting. Asks him to read Curators' report if necessary.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 21, 1893; 6x6; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Defer reading of Curators' report on damage to collections until J.S. Price can be present. On same sheet is letter from Morris to Price, May 5, 1893.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, April 21, 1893; 8-1/2x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. (see APS Curators. Reports) Please defer action on Curators' report on damage to collections until he can be present.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1893; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Cannot attend meeting. Concerns report of Curators, and reply of Committee on Hall Refers to Morris, Fraley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 23, 1893; 6-1/4x3-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of program of A.P.S. sesquicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 24, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. and end. Asks to give paper on atmospheric physics at A.P.S. sesquicentennial celebration. Refers to Price.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25, 1893; 5-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of Boas' paper on the Kwakiutl Indian language. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 34-82.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 26, 1893; 8x5; Gentry, Thomas G. (Thomas George), 1843-1905
    [Phila.?], A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about his paper of "The Higher Fungi of Philadelphia." Paper presented by E.D. Cope on April 7, 1893. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 136, 251.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 26, 1893; 10x8; Texas Academy of Science
    Austin, Texas, A.L.S.: Alexander Macfarlane. 1p., end. Encs. wanting. Sends receipt and a brochure.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1893; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 3p. Appoints W.J. Potts to prepare obituary of T.H. Dudley. Inquires if W.H. Furness ever resigned his membership.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 28, 1893; 8x5; Bakewell, B. G.
    Pittsburgh, [Pa.], A.L.S. 4p., end. Inquires if William Bakewell was connected with the Society. Refers to Priestley, Audubon, E. Darwin, A.H. Wharton.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 28, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Canden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks for copy of Fraley's questions used in conducting A.P.S. meetings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 29, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Discusses terms of Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 1, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2, 8-1/2x5-1/2; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. Concerns his subscription to the Proceedings. Returns signed form.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 1, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J. A.L.S. 4p. Will prepare obituary of T.H. Dudley.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 3, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Nolan, Edward James, 1846-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks death date of T.H. Dudley.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 3, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Will send promised books soon.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 3, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for quote on complete set of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 3, 1893; 13x8-1/4; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, L.S.: [Eduard] Suess, [Alfred, Ritter von] Arneth 2p., end. In German. Letter to congratulations on Sesquicentennial celebration. For printed letter, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 54-56.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1893; 11x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends portrait of Mathew Carey, a copy of that by Neagle.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, May 5, 1893; 6x6; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Read Curators'report on damage to collections "pro forma" adding Price's explanation. Written at foot of sheet containing letter from Morris to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1893.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 6, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Literary press bureau
    Chicago, L. 1p., end. Inquires about history of A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], May 8, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Salem, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Encs. wanting. Thanks him and A.P.S. for publishing his paper on Saprolegniaceae. Sends receipts for Proceedings. For Printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 63-148.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 9, 1893; 8x5-1/4; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: Geo[rge] Maurice Abbot, Treas. 1p. Asks for copies of Proceedings which contain early minutes and the account of the anniversary dinner.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], May 11, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Macfarlane, John Muirhead, 1855-1943
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns a paper sent in for publication. Refers to W.P. Wilson.
  - Notice of death of William Holmes Chambers Bartlett, May 11, 1893
    A.D. 1p.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 13, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2; University of Pennsylvania
    [Phila.], L. 1p., end. Concerns correct form of C.R. Gregory's name.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], May 15, 1893; 8x5; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.: Josiah P[arsons] Cooke 1p. Presents Alpheus Hyatt as delegate to coming celebration of A.P.S. sesquicentennial.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will speak on evidences of primitive man in America at next meeting. For remarks, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp.229-231.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 17, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p., end. Is delegate from Academy of Arts and Sciences to A.P.S. Sesquicentennial. Asks about presenting a paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 17, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895